<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gennady Uraltsev</title>
    <link>https://guraltsev.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gennady Uraltsev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guraltsev.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rough paths and regularity structures applied to probabilistic PDEs</title>
      <link>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-rough-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-rough-paths/</guid>
      <description>Meeting times When: Friday 11:15 - 12:45ish
Where: Kerchof 326
If interested contact Gennady Uraltsev and Juraj Földes.
We can consider remote participation via Zoom should interest arise. Feel free to circulate.
Collab site
Summary Martin Hairer received the Fields medal at the ICM in Seoul 2014 for “his outstanding contributions to the theory of stochastic partial differential equations&amp;quot; (quoted from the ICM webpage), in particular for the creation of the theory of regularity structures1.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="meeting-times">Meeting times</h2>
<p>When: Friday 11:15 - 12:45ish</p>
<p>Where: Kerchof 326</p>
<p>If interested contact <a href="mailto:gu8gs@virginia.edu">Gennady Uraltsev</a> and <a href="mailto:jf8dc@virginia.edu">Juraj Földes</a>.</p>
<p>We can consider remote participation via Zoom should interest arise.
Feel free to circulate.</p>
<p><a href="https://collab.its.virginia.edu/portal/site/a5e4a36f-6f7c-490e-8c0b-e314344fa33e">Collab site</a></p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Martin Hairer received the Fields medal at the ICM in Seoul 2014 for “his outstanding contributions to the theory of stochastic partial differential equations&quot; (quoted from the ICM webpage), in particular for the creation of the theory of regularity structures<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. The theory of regularity structures formally subsumes Terry Lyons&rsquo; theory of rough paths<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> and is particularly adapted to solving stochastic parabolic equations<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>. A more analytic generalization of rough paths has been developed by Gubinelli et. al. in the form of paracontrolled calculus<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> and has proven applicable to stochastic PDE with dispersive behavior<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup>.</p>
<p>The goal of this reading seminar is to gain an understanding of the relation of the results panorama of singular stochastic PDEs with particular attention to the results above. We will mainly concentrate on the classic Terry Lyons&rsquo; theory and its subsequent development in terms of paracontrolled calculus. In particular, we will follow lecture notes by Gubinelli<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup> and the intro book<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8</a></sup> by Hairer and Friz. This starts mainly with ODE theory. We will then try to progress to SPDEs (parabolic) by following<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9</a></sup>. Finally, it might be interesting to present how these ideas are applied to dispersive PDE<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">10</a></sup> <sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">11</a></sup> and also to compare paracontrolled theory with Hairer&rsquo;s regularity structures<sup id="fnref1:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8</a></sup> <sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Gennady has previously partially followed a course and taught on closely related topics so he would gladly provide lectures in the beginning. Initiative to present topics further down the road is appreciated but not required.</p>
<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>
<ul>
<li>A solid background in Lebesgue integration theory and classical analysis.</li>
<li>Exposure to probability and stochastic analysis is suggested.</li>
</ul>
<p>We plan on developing pathwise stochastic integration in this context but a certain general familiarity with the Brownian motion and Ito&rsquo;s formula is suggested.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Basics of Fourier analysis is required:</p>
<ul>
<li>$L^2$ theory</li>
<li>theory of distributions</li>
<li>generalized functions and Sobolev spaces (will be reviewed quickly)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Exposure to basic PDEs (heat, wave) is encouraged (especially starting from the second part of the seminar).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="additional-material">Additional material</h3>
<p>In the meantime, to get an informal introduction of the relation of rough path theory to applications outside of math please enjoy the following talk:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nEflrmcIwh0">What has rough paths got to do with data science - Terry Lyons - YouTube</a></p>
<p>Other interesting material (that will probably not be covered in the seminar):</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.quantstart.com/articles/rough-path-theory-and-signatures-applied-to-quantitative-finance-part-1/">Rough Path Theory and Signatures Applied To Quantitative Finance - Part 1 | QuantStart</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We are open to suggestions on closely related topics.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Hairer, Martin. &ldquo;A theory of regularity structures.&rdquo; Inventiones mathematicae 198.2 (2014): 269-504.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rough_path">Rough path - Wikipedia</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Lyons, T., &amp; Qian, Z. (2002). &ldquo;System control and rough paths&rdquo;. Oxford : New York: Clarendon Press ; Oxford University Press.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kardar%E2%80%93Parisi%E2%80%93Zhang_equation">Kardar–Parisi–Zhang equation - Wikipedia</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Gubinelli, Massimiliano, Peter Imkeller, and Nicolas Perkowski. &ldquo;Paracontrolled distributions and singular PDEs.&rdquo; Forum of Mathematics, Pi. Vol. 3. Cambridge University Press, 2015.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Gubinelli, M., et al. &ldquo;Global dynamics for the two-dimensional stochastic nonlinear wave equations, to appear in Internat.&rdquo; Math. Res. Not.&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>Unpublished lecture notes&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p><a href="https://www.hairer.org/notes/RoughPaths.pdf">RoughPaths.pdf (hairer.org)</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:8" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:8" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p>Gubinelli, Massimiliano, and Nicolas Perkowski. &ldquo;Lectures on singular stochastic PDEs.&rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1502.00157 (2015).&#160;<a href="#fnref:9" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p>Gubinelli, Massimiliano, Herbert Koch, and Tadahiro Oh. &ldquo;Paracontrolled approach to the three-dimensional stochastic nonlinear wave equation with quadratic nonlinearity.&rdquo; <a href="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1811.07808">arXiv preprint arXiv:1811.07808 (2018)</a>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:10" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:11">
<p>Gubinelli, Massimiliano, B. Ugurcan, and Immanuel Zachhuber. &ldquo;Semilinear evolution equations for the Anderson Hamiltonian in two and three dimensions.&rdquo; Stochastics and Partial Differential Equations: Analysis and Computations 8.1 (2020): 82-149.&#160;<a href="#fnref:11" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculus 3 (MATH2310) - Assessment </title>
      <link>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/assessment/</guid>
      <description>Homework There will be weekly homework assignments due on Tuesday night. The weekly homework will involve:
online exercise (Cengage - Webassign), written homework assignments to be turned in through Gradescope, Throughout the semester there will be several periodic additional projects:
group video presentations Consistent effort on homework is vital to the success in the course and the homework assessment represents a significant portion of the final grade. Use this to your advantage: we welcome discussion and questions about homework assignments during office hours and on Piazza.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="homework">Homework</h3>
<p>There will be weekly homework assignments due on Tuesday night. The weekly homework will involve:</p>
<ul>
<li>online exercise (<a href="https://www.webassign.net/">Cengage - Webassign</a>),</li>
<li>written homework assignments to be turned in through <a href="https://collab.its.virginia.edu/portal/site/919a961a-6bab-40d8-9d89-a51d89d52296/page/f40b44f1-c9a0-4f3e-9f80-c85157254942">Gradescope</a>,</li>
</ul>
<p>Throughout the semester there will be several periodic additional projects:</p>
<ul>
<li>group video presentations</li>
</ul>
<p>Consistent effort on homework is vital to the success in the course and the homework assessment represents a significant portion of the final grade. Use this to your advantage: we welcome discussion and questions about homework assignments during office hours and on Piazza. Homework deadlines should be respected, however small extensions may be considered in case of necessity.</p>
<p>You are <strong>encouraged</strong> to study and work together with your peers on HW assignments. Explaining your though process and figuring things out together often helps with understanding and mastering the material. Everyone should turn in their own copy, unless specified otherwise. You <strong>MUST</strong> acknowledge any collaboration and external sources used.</p>
<p>Failure to acknowledge help or external references constitutes an <em>Academic integrity violation</em>.  If you forget to acknowledge sources of help, please do so as soon as you remember.</p>
<h3 id="examination">Examination</h3>
<p>The course will have 2 proctored midterm exams (90 minutes) and 1 final exam. The midterms will occur outside standard class time, in the evening (starting at 18:30). The dates will be published shortly after the beginning of the course.  In case of conflicts, you must reach out as soon as possible and no less than 7 working days before the scheduled midterm. Missing a midterm will result in a grade of 0 for that assignment. No makeup opportunities will be allowed if not agreed upon beforehand.</p>
<p>The midterms and final are <em>open book</em>. You are allowed to use the course book, published course material (e.g. HW solutions), and any personal notes you have taken when studying. No other external material is allowed. Please prepare in a timely manner</p>
<p>More details will be provided closer to the examination dates</p>
<h3 id="grades">Grades</h3>
<p>Your final grade will be computed according to the following proportions (subject to minor modification).</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Grade composition (subject to change)</th>
<th></th>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Homework-Webassign</td>
<td>25%</td>
<td>(worst 2 homework grades dropped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Homework-Handin</td>
<td>25%</td>
<td>(worst 2 homework grades dropped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Midterm 01</td>
<td>10%</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Midterm 02</td>
<td>10%</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Final</td>
<td>15%</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Other</td>
<td>15%</td>
<td>recorded presentations and other assignments.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Several times during the course you will receive information about approximate letter grade cutoffs. These are subject to modification and provided only for your information. The final grade cutoffs are established at the end of the course.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculus 3 (MATH2310) - Course summary </title>
      <link>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/summary/</guid>
      <description>​
The course is an introduction to calculus of functions of several variables. In lower level calculus classes students have learned how to deal with (real) numbers and functions from $\mathbb{R}$ to $\mathbb{R}$. While full of very deep results, that knowledge falls short of providing the necessary tools to deal with most real life scientific application because our world is more correctly described by 2, 3, or 4-dimensional space. This course, Calculus 3 (multivariable calculus), extends the knowledge from 1 dimensional calculus to allow us to understand how to model and to do computations (integrals, derivatives) for paths, on surfaces, volumes (a.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>​</p>
<p>The course is an introduction to calculus of functions of several variables. In lower level calculus classes students have learned how to deal with (real) numbers and functions from $\mathbb{R}$ to $\mathbb{R}$. While full of very deep results, that knowledge falls short of providing the necessary tools to deal with most real life scientific application because our world is more correctly described by 2, 3, or 4-dimensional space. </p>
<p>This course, Calculus 3 (multivariable calculus), extends the knowledge from 1 dimensional calculus to allow us to understand how to model and to do computations (integrals, derivatives) for paths, on surfaces, volumes (a.k.a. solids).</p>
<h1 id="topics">Topics</h1>
<h2 id="geometry-of-space">Geometry of space</h2>
<p>The course starts with discussing the geometry of 2D and 3D space. How does one describe the position in space? How does one describe motion in space as times goes by?  How does one describe mathematically a portion of a doughnut covered in chocolate glazing? What is 2D and 3D space, anyway?</p>
<p>We will quickly cover basics of vector algebra: how does one add and multiply vectors? What is a dot product? What is a cross product? What do these objects represent?</p>
<p>We will also discuss basics of linear algebra in 2D and 3D: how do you describe a line in 2D? How do you describe a plane in 3D? How do you check whether three points lie on the same line?</p>
<h2 id="paths">Paths</h2>
<p>In this section we focus on motion in space. Now our functions will take &ldquo;time&rdquo; as an input and give a position in space as an output. In this section we will first encounter derivatives and integrals in the setting of multivariable calculus.</p>
<h2 id="multivariable-calculus-techniques">Multivariable calculus techniques</h2>
<p>Next, we move to extend the notions from differential calculus to functions defined on 2D and 3D space.</p>
<p>These functions can be used to model important quantities like:</p>
<ul>
<li>elevation a mountain range depending on $x,y$ position on a map</li>
<li>temperature at every point in a room</li>
</ul>
<p>We will talk about continuity, derivatives (partial derivatives), maxima, minima, and critical points of multi-variable functions.</p>
<p>We will learn the meaning of:</p>
<ul>
<li>gradient</li>
<li>gradient field</li>
<li>level set</li>
<li>contour plot</li>
<li>graph</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="multivariable-integration">Multivariable integration</h2>
<p>After understanding multivariable differentiation we will introduce and learn how to compute integrals in multiple variables. In 1D calculus the definite integral was a tool to compute areas under curves. We will understand what is the geometric meaning and properties of the integral in multiple dimensions. We will then learn how to actually do computations with 2D and 3D integrals.</p>
<h2 id="different-versions-of-stokes-theorem">Different versions of Stokes&rsquo; theorem</h2>
<p>The culmination of 1D calculus is the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus that relates the (definite) integral to the derivative. The theorem essentially states that the two operations: computing the derivative and computing the integral are one the opposite of the other. A very deep connection exists between integrals and derivatives in 2D and 3D but due to the different shapes that exist in space the theorem is more involved and the applications are countless!</p>
<h1 id="questions-that-the-course-addresses">Questions that the course addresses</h1>
<ol>
<li>Suppose I have a topographical map (describes elevation of terrain); how do I correctly describe the slope of the mountain that I see on the map?</li>
<li>What are those closed lines (contour lines) on a topographical map?</li>
<li>I know how to find the maximum value of a function on $\mathbb{R}$ using derivatives. What if my function describes the temperature at every point in 3D space: what should I use instead of a derivative to find the place where the temperature is highest?</li>
<li>What if my function is only defined on a surface e.g. I know what the temperature at each point on the surface of the Earth (that is round, b.t.w.) is? How do I use derivatives to figure out which is the coldest place on Earth?</li>
<li>How much work against gravity is it to climb a given mountain? Does it depend on the path one takes?</li>
<li>What is the area of the surface of the Earth? What is it&rsquo;s volume? Where do the formulae: $4/3 \pi r^3$ for the volume of a ball and $4\pi r^2$ for the surface area of a sphere come from?</li>
<li>I know Calculus 1: it seems that if I take the derivative of the first formula I obtain the second one. Is this a coincidence? Are there any such cool relations for other shapes?</li>
<li>Someone described a polygon on the plane to me by giving me the (x,y) coordinates of each corner. I need to compute the area of the polygon, can I do it quickly or do I have to draw it to understand how the shape looks like? After all the polygon can be convex: <img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/04/Pentagon.svg/500px-Pentagon.svg.png" alt="500px-Pentagon.svg.png"  />
<img loading="lazy" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAPABAP///wAAACH5BAEKAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAICRAEAOw==" alt=""  title="Click and drag to move"  />
​ 
but it could also be concave like this: <img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8f/Simple_polygon.svg/1200px-Simple_polygon.svg.png" alt="1200px-Simple_polygon.svg.png"  />
<img loading="lazy" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAPABAP///wAAACH5BAEKAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAICRAEAOw==" alt=""  title="Click and drag to move"  />
​</li>
<li>A piece of paper has two sides. The surface of a ball has two sides (outside and inside). Is it true that any surface in 3D has two sides? Can it have one side? </li>
<li>Is the surface of a soap bubble floating through (3D) space a 2D or 3D object?</li>
<li>Why can I take the cross product of two 3D vectors and obtain vector, but if I take the cross product of two 2D vectors I get a number?</li>
<li>Why can I always take the dot product of two vectors in 2D or in 3D and always get just a number?</li>
<li>What is a cross product, anyway?</li>
</ol>
<p>​</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculus 3 (MATH2310) - How to succede </title>
      <link>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/how-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guraltsev.github.io/teaching/fa22-math2310/how-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>This course moves quickly. It is very important to stay abreast of the current topics and not to fall behind.
Particular emphasis is placed on students developing visualization and geometric intuition. Computations are present but are not the focus of the course. This is not a proof-based course, but students are expected to be able to justify their reasoning. Solving problems may require putting together multiple ideas from the course, sometimes in unexpected ways.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This course <em>moves quickly</em>. It is very important to stay abreast of the current topics and not to fall behind.</p>
<p>Particular emphasis is placed on students developing visualization and geometric intuition. Computations are present but are not the focus of the course. This is not a proof-based course, but students are expected to be able to justify their reasoning. Solving problems may require putting together multiple ideas from the course, sometimes in unexpected ways.</p>
<p>Students are encouraged to learn to use computer tools to carry out computations unless explicitly requested not to. Consider exploring the following tools:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.geogebra.org/?lang=en">GeoGebra - the world&rsquo;s favorite, free math tools</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.wolframalpha.com/">Wolfram Alpha: Computational Intelligence (wolframalpha.com)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.desmos.com/">Desmos - Let&rsquo;s learn together</a></li>
<li><a href="https://colab.research.google.com/">Welcome To Colaboratory - Colaboratory (google.com)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You will be provided with a lot of material:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dedicate significant independent study time to the material covered. Not everything will be covered explicitly in during lecture: we will let you know when you should read up on some topics on your own</li>
<li>The lesson-by-lesson syllabus will contain indications of topics, examples, and links to additional material. Carefully check the syllabus both after and before the lecture to make sure you do not miss anything.</li>
<li>Try to skim through the book or watch a youtube video (links and suggestions will be provided) on the topics of the coming week. It is much easier to learn if you already know what approximately is going on.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="attend-office-hours">Attend office hours</h2>
<p>Please attend office hours! Office hours gives you individual attention that you cannot get from reading the textbook or watching an explanatory YouTube video.</p>
<p>You are welcome to ask questions about the course material, about any other related topic, and about the assignments. We are glad to help you if you are stuck! Do not worry, we will not hold any questions you ask against you. If you are not able to attend regularly scheduled office hours, please reach out. Office hours by appointment will be considered.</p>
<p>Attending office hours is not a sign of weakness. If no one has specific questions we will take up the time by discussing the homework problems together!</p>
<h2 id="piazza">Piazza</h2>
<p>Help is available from your peers and instructors through <a href="https://collab.its.virginia.edu/portal/site/919a961a-6bab-40d8-9d89-a51d89d52296/page/fac16fa6-ade4-4f3e-b05f-bc25afe7f99a">Piazza</a>, an online forum.</p>
<p>You can post publicly or privately, anonymously or under your own name. We will try to respond to your concerns or questions there even outside office hours. You, students, are also encouraged to share your thoughts and understanding there. Please familiarize yourself with the platform.</p>
<h2 id="mclc">MCLC</h2>
<p>There is FREE math help available on grounds from the <a href="https://math.virginia.edu/undergraduate/MCLC/">Math Collaborative Learning Center</a>.</p>
<h2 id="practice-problems">Practice problems</h2>
<p>Online HW problems are simpler and are meant to develop basic skills and familiarity with new concepts with run-of-the-mill problems.</p>
<p>Written HW assignments require you to put together what you have learned.</p>
<p>Work through the online HW first. If feel like you need more practice, additional problems (graded automatically by the system, with no weight on the course grade) are available.</p>
<h2 id="work-together">Work together</h2>
<p>Find a study buddy! Work together, discuss your understanding, check each other&rsquo;s work. You are encouraged to work together on HW and study together.</p>
<p>Some homework assignments will require one submission per group students so get to know your pears.</p>
<p>You are not competing with each other. We have time-tested standards for course performance and are more than happy to award higher grades if everyone is successful. We do not have to meet specific grade distributions.</p>
<p>Try out asking a question there or attempting to answer someone else&rsquo;s question on <a href="https://collab.its.virginia.edu/portal/site/5b6663ee-59e7-4b4f-b2f1-b60e3d303b22/page/c075cb47-e0f2-48b8-8ff0-b8a8a53c98d0?sakai.popup=yes">Piazza</a>. Do not worry if your answer might be incomplete or wrong. We will help you out, clarify doubts. You can always post anonymously but do consider putting your name on your posts: it makes math a bit more human.</p>
<h2 id="ask-questions">Ask questions</h2>
<p><strong>Ask questions!</strong> Raise your hand or if we do not notice, interrupt us! If we need to finish a concept before responding, we will respectfully tell you and address your concern as soon as we can. There are no bad questions. Let us know if you are lost trying to understand. Questions do not have to be specific to a step in the course material; examples of good questions are:</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>Why does this seemingly simpler approach not work here?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Maybe you are onto something: do not trust the instructor to be infallible</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>You are using words that you have not used before, what do these words even mean?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Math is a language and learning to do math is learning to speak a language. Gaining a good amount of lexicon is important!)</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>Can you draw a picture?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pictures are important!</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>If I had to to solve this problem without having heard this explanation, how would I go about coming up with a solution?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is ultimately what you need to learn. Knowing specific facts might not be useful for you in your future but problem-solving skills are!</p>
<hr>
<p>As long as you ask because you actually want to learn and are respectful of everyone in attendance, you are in the clear.</p>
<h2 id="honor-code">Honor Code</h2>
<p>The  <a href="https://honor.virginia.edu/">University of Virginia Honor Code</a> applies to this class and is taken seriously. Any honor code violations will be referred to the Honor Committee. Upon submission of each assignment in this class you pledge to abide by the rules of UVA, this course, and the specific assignment. If you have doubts, please ask on <a href="https://guraltsev-teaching.gitlab.io/math2310-200-2020fa/#org02f1e04">Piazza</a>.</p>
<p>You MUST acknowledge any help you received on assignments, even if it is permitted e.g. you worked with a fellow student, looked up things online, etc. Not acknowledging external help is an Honor Code violation.</p>
<h2 id="well-being">Well-being</h2>
<p>This course progresses quickly and at times you might feel lost; this is normal. The instructor is available both to answer your doubts about the course material and suggest ways to approach studying and coursework. Math is hard: struggling is part of doing math, and it means you are pushing yourself to be your best.</p>
<p>UVA also provides resources if you are feeling overwhelmed, stressed, or isolated. The Student Health and Wellness Center offers <a href="https://studenthealth.virginia.edu/caps">Counseling and Psychological Services (CAPS)</a> for its students; call 434-243-5150 to speak with an on-call counselor and/or schedule an appointment. If you prefer to speak anonymously, you can call Madison House&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.helplineuva.com/">HELP Line</a> at any hour of any day: 434-295-TALK. Alternatively, you can call or text the <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/find-help/disaster-distress-helpline">Disaster Distress Helpline</a> (1-800-985-5990, or text TalkWithUs to 66746) to connect with a trained crisis counselor; this is toll free, multilingual, and confidential, available to all residents in the US and its territories.</p>
<h2 id="accommodation">Accommodation</h2>
<p>All students with special needs requiring accommodations should present the appropriate paperwork from the Student Disability Access Center (SDAC). It is the student&rsquo;s responsibility to present this paperwork in a timely fashion and follow up with the instructor about the accommodations being offered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
